A Guide to the John Barnes Letters
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #564-a and -b
John Barnes Letters 1798-1805 Inclusive
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
Collection number 564-a and -b
10 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research
Acquisition Information
Purchase 1988 April 15 & 1988 April 21
Container List
- Letters
  - John Barnes, Philadelphia, to Charles C. Ludlow, New York, 1798 April 15
    concerning the enclosures that the latter had sent previously which needed Col. [Aaron] Burr's decision
  - John Barnes, George Town (Potomac), to Charles C. Ludlow, New York, 1800 October 31
    noting that a problem with one of their transactions was resolved; and, discussing his options for obtaining sugar from suppliers in Philadelphia, Baltimore, or the immediate area if negotiations do not work out with Mr. Seaman
  - John Barnes, George Town, to Charles C. Ludlow, New York, 1801 April 8
    concerning a misunderstanding on the part of his friend, Mr. Dean, regarding a draft that was to be sent to Mr. Thomas Legget; and, a fragment pertaining to the purchase of a variety of spirits--Madeira, sherry, port, Cognac--if a bargain can be struck, along with other "merchantable articles" in current use
  - John Barnes, George Town, to Charles C. Ludlow, New York, 1801 May 5
    writing that his good port wine supply is exhausted, revealing that the President [ Thomas Jefferson] and Mr. [James] Madison both approved of it, and requesting more; negotiating to buy $2000.00 worth of late deferred stock or other reasonable stock as someone's agent, to be transferred to the Bank of Columbia; discussing a financial transaction subject to the order of Philip Mazzei; and, mentioning Gen. [Thaddeus] Kosciusko
  - John Barnes, George Town, to Charles C. Ludlow, New York, 1802 June 22
    acknowledging receipt of his letter concerning Mr. William Short's certificate and thanking him for his helpful negotiations; commenting on the unproductive undertaking of doing business there and wanting to resume his "former peaceable situation at Philadelphia"
  - John Barnes, George Town (Potomac), to Charles C. Ludlow, New York, 1805 May 28
    mentioning a business transaction concerning Mr. Hazzard and the President [ Thomas Jefferson]; negotiating to have sent to him some imported wine from the House of Mr. Woodhouse at Marsalla in Sicily(known as Marsalla Madeira Wine), which was brought in by Gen. [ ] Stevens and sent to Gen. [Henry] Dearborn, with postscript commenting that Henry Dearborn is a good judge of wine
  - John Barnes, George Town, to Charles C. Ludlow, New York, 1805 June 15
    thanking him for the attention given to the [Marsalla Madeira] Wines and commenting that Gen. Henry Dearborn, at his request, sent samples of the wine, and making arrangments to have wine and Cognac delivered in July or August; planning to send $300.00 to cover expenses and another account; and, mentioning business transactions for the President [ Thomas Jefferson]
  - John Barnes, George Town (Potomac), to Charles C. Ludlow, New York, 1805 July 6
    enclosing the $300.00 for the pipes of M[arsalla] M[adeira] Wine and Cognac as well as for Mr. Cheetham; discussing a mistake made previously "owing to the advice of the President to Mr. Hazzard not designating C. Ludlow from D. Ludlow" and the subsequent adjustment made; requesting arrangments be made with Gen. Stevens to have the wine shipped to George Town
  - John Barnes, George Town (Potomac), to Charles C. Ludlow, New York, 1805 August 20
    acknowledging news that wine and brandy were shipped on the schooner Enterprize
  - John Barnes, George Town, to Charles C. Ludlow, New York, 1805 August 22
    discussing a problem with Capt. Ellis of the Enterprize over payment of extra freight from Alexandria to Georgetown; acknowledging receipt of the invoice from Charles C. Ludlow and saying that it is satisfactory; and, sending thanks from himself and on behalf of the President [ Thomas Jefferson]